<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 20:14:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Frequentism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/frequentism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:43:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/frequentism/</guid>
      <description>Next, we examine the second main, contemporary approach to scientific reasoning, based in the frequentist understanding of probability. At the heart of its reasoning is the “double negative” inference, based in the “probabilistic modus tollens.” The jargon name for this approach is “null hypothesis significance testing.” We will observe how and why it works, building up from some foundational concepts.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 16 “Stability” Hacking, Chapter 17 “Normal Approximations” Hacking, Chapter 18 “Significance and Power” (note on type I/II error)  Slides (slide links to come — not live yet)</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Bayesianism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:42:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</guid>
      <description>Bayesianism, as an approach to inductive reasoning, focuses on updating our beliefs in light of new evidence. It is built around a simple formula that expreses a relationship between probabilities.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 7 “Bayes&#39; Rule” (pages 69–77) Hacking, Chapter 13 “Personal Probabilities” (pages 151–160) Hacking, Chapter 21 “Learning from Experience as an Evasion of the Problem of Induction” (4 pages) — and if you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling sufficiently familiar with “the problem of induction,” look at the first pages of Chapter 20  See also  John Horgan, “Bayes&amp;rsquo;s Theorem: What&amp;rsquo;s the Big Deal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Probability</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Feb 2021 13:34:49 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</guid>
      <description>Here we set up some basic ideas about probability which will be key for understanding the approaches to scientific justification which have dominated the last several decades.
Reading  Hacking, Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic  Chapter 3 “The Gambler&amp;rsquo;s Fallacy”  This chapter introduces the basic concepts randomness, independence, and probability model but overall it&amp;rsquo;s pitched to give you a feel for some probability ideas. You might read it more quickly than Chapter 4↓.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:19:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</guid>
      <description>Upload your page to “Assignment 1” on Blackboard, under the Assignments area (link in the left sidebar) by, at the latest, (anytime on) Feb 19.
Tasks   For this exercise, arguments take the form of two or more sentences — with at least three usually making things easier! — the last of which is the conclusion. The phrases in each sentence should fit together. See forallx, Chapter 2 for examples of arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:56:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/resources/</guid>
      <description>Hofstra  Minor in Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning Philosophy Department  Online, open-access books to learn from  Odds &amp;amp; Ends: Introducing Probability &amp;amp; Decision with a Visual Emphasis, by Jonthan Weisberg Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction, by Kieran Healy Grinstead and Snell’s Introduction to Probability, by Peter G. Doyle, Charles M. Grinstead and J. Laurie Snell OpenIntro Statistics, by David M. Diez et al. Introductory Statistics for the Life and Biomedical Sciences, a derivative of OpenIntro, above Online Statistics Education: An Interactive Multimedia Course of Study, by David M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 2 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 10:41:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our second test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list; it&amp;rsquo;s now complete. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 1 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:30:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our first test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Early Methods</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:59:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</guid>
      <description>As modern science emerged, its practitioners tried to describe how they were reasoning, and how others should reason, to do science. They came to quite different answers! This unit looks quickly at a few landmarks from the period 1600–1900.
Reading  Francis Bacon, The New Organon (1620). Read Book 2, sections 10–16, starting on page 53 of the linked PDF. Focus on the figuring out the meaning of the beginning and end of the reading, and skim through the content in the middle to get a general sense of what&amp;rsquo;s going.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:23:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</guid>
      <description>Could deductive logic be the logic of science? What is logic? And what is deductive logic? Is non-deductive logic possible?
Reading (This is what you should read for this section. The due dates appear on the front page schedule.)
 forallx Calgary: An Introduction to Formal Logic, Fall 2020 edition, by Magnus et al. Get PDF from here, available in several versions; or, here is a direct link to the the screen-friendly PDF version.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:25:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one written by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
