<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Jul 2021 20:14:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Probability</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 10:18:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</guid>
      <description>Here we set up some basic ideas about probability which will are necessary for understanding the approaches to scientific justification scientists have used most during the last fifty years.
Reading  Hacking, Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic  Chapter 3 “The Gambler&amp;rsquo;s Fallacy”  This chapter introduces the basic concepts randomness, independence, and probability model but overall it&amp;rsquo;s pitched to give you a feel for some probability ideas. You might read it more quickly than Chapter 4↓.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:34:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 2” by February 16.
Tasks   Find the brief sketch of scientific method you wrote out during our exercise in class.1 Write that out briefly.2 (about 3–4 sentences)
  Look at the steps in, or parts of, your representation of scientific method. Do any of the moves involve deductive reasoning? Do any of the moves involve inductive reasoning? (By “moves” I mean: If someone were to try to do science using your method, what are the steps they would probably take?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Early Methods</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 14:22:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</guid>
      <description>As modern science emerged, its practitioners tried to describe how they were reasoning, and how others should reason, to do science. They came to quite different answers! This unit looks quickly at a few landmarks from the period 1600–1900.
Reading  Francis Bacon, The New Organon (1620). Read Book 2, sections 10–16 (bottom right of page 53 to page 64 of the linked PDF). Focus on the figuring out the meaning of the beginning and end of the reading, and skim through the content in the middle to get a general sense of what&amp;rsquo;s going, and then attend more closely to the conclusion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:17:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one shared by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:17:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:16:17 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</guid>
      <description>Does science have a logic? Could it be what we call “deductive logic,” which is the focus of PHI 154? What is deductive logic? Is non-deductive logic possible? What could “inductive logic” be? Could it be the logic of science?
Reading (This is what you should read for this section. The due dates appear on the front page schedule.)
 forallx Calgary: An Introduction to Formal Logic, Fall 2020 edition, by Magnus et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 7: Decision Theory</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/decision-theory/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 May 2021 14:30:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/decision-theory/</guid>
      <description>Decision theory offers a framework for using knowledge to make decisions. To do this, it offers a way of integrating probabilities and values. And it offers some guidelines for choosing different probability/value combinations under different conditions.
Reading  Hacking, “Expected Value,” chapter 8 of Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic. Read pages 79–82 with care. Hacking, “Maximizing Expected Value,” chapter 9 of Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic. Read pages 98–108.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 1 Information</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tests/test-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Mar 2021 14:02:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tests/test-1/</guid>
      <description>Our first test will, unless circumstances intervene, take place during class on DATE COMING SOON.
Further information coming soon.
How to study To study for the test review and think about the answers to the Learning Questions for each of our units to date, and try to find the main arguments for each of the readings and/or class presentations. On the test you will be asked to explain some ideas closely related to the answers of those Learning Questions, with some eye to integration among the topics — to how they might be understood as answer to the same, more general questions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Frequentism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/frequentism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:43:16 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/frequentism/</guid>
      <description>Next, we examine the second main, contemporary approach to scientific reasoning, based in the frequentist understanding of probability. At the heart of its reasoning is the “double negative” inference, based in the “probabilistic modus tollens.” The jargon name for this approach is “null hypothesis significance testing.” We will observe how and why it works, building up from some foundational concepts.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 16 “Stability” Hacking, Chapter 17 “Normal Approximations” Hacking, Chapter 18 “Significance and Power” (note on type I/II error)  Slides  Introducing null-hypothesis testing Introduction to population sampling and correlation  Learning questions  How does the relative frequency interpretation of probability give rise to a way of justifying scientific knowledge?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Bayesianism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Feb 2021 14:42:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</guid>
      <description>Bayesianism, as an approach to inductive reasoning, focuses on updating our beliefs in light of new evidence. It is built around a simple formula that expresses a relationship between probabilities.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 7 “Bayes&#39; Rule” (pages 69–77) Hacking, Chapter 13 “Personal Probabilities” (pages 151–160) Hacking, Chapter 21 “Learning from Experience as an Evasion of the Problem of Induction” (4 pages) — and if you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling sufficiently familiar with “the problem of induction” (from our discussion of Hume), optionally look at the first pages of Chapter 20  Slides  Introducing Bayesianism  Learning questions  What do each of the terms mean in the basic version of Bayes&amp;rsquo;s Rule?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:19:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</guid>
      <description>Upload your page to “Assignment 1” on Blackboard, under the Assignments area (link in the left sidebar) by, at the latest, (anytime on) February 9.
Tasks   For this exercise, arguments take the form of two or more sentences — with at least three usually making things easier! — the last of which is the conclusion. The phrases in each sentence should fit together. See (assigned reading) forallx, Chapter 2 for examples of arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:56:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/resources/</guid>
      <description>Hofstra  Minor in Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning Philosophy Department  Online, open-access books to learn from  Odds &amp;amp; Ends: Introducing Probability &amp;amp; Decision with a Visual Emphasis, by Jonthan Weisberg Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction, by Kieran Healy Grinstead and Snell’s Introduction to Probability, by Peter G. Doyle, Charles M. Grinstead and J. Laurie Snell OpenIntro Statistics, by David M. Diez et al. Introductory Statistics for the Life and Biomedical Sciences, a derivative of OpenIntro, above Online Statistics Education: An Interactive Multimedia Course of Study, by David M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 6: Causation</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/causation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:09:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/causation/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve discussed what correlations are, and how they are related to sampling from a population via basic probability ideas. But we noted that correlation isn&amp;rsquo;t causation, and that researchers are quite often interested in causation. Here we take up how it might be possible to investigate causal relationships, and some of the challenges and limitations inherent to doing that.
Reading  Kara Richardson. from “Avicenna’s Necessitation Thesis” (see Causation Readings) David Hume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 2 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 10:41:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our second test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list; it&amp;rsquo;s now complete. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 1 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:30:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our first test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
