<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 26 Jan 2021 20:14:36 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Resources</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/resources/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Jan 2021 14:56:42 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/resources/</guid>
      <description>Hofstra  Minor in Data Analysis and Scientific Reasoning Philosophy Department  Online, open-access books to learn from  Odds &amp;amp; Ends: Introducing Probability &amp;amp; Decision with a Visual Emphasis, by Jonthan Weisberg Data Visualization: A Practical Introduction, by Kieran Healy Grinstead and Snell’s Introduction to Probability, by Peter G. Doyle, Charles M. Grinstead and J. Laurie Snell OpenIntro Statistics, by David M. Diez et al. Introductory Statistics for the Life and Biomedical Sciences, a derivative of OpenIntro, above Online Statistics Education: An Interactive Multimedia Course of Study, by David M.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Natural Deduction with Derived Rules Answers</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/natural-deduction-with-derived-rules-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 25 Nov 2020 12:50:54 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/natural-deduction-with-derived-rules-answers/</guid>
      <description>Proof-solutions for the exercise on TFL natural deduction with derived rules is → here.
An important caveat: these are only the solutions I happened to see first, and which seemed to me at least as efficient as other solutions I immediately saw. There are always many other solutions, and especially many other legitimate ways of ordering inferences. So, your answer that&amp;rsquo;s quite unlike what I&amp;rsquo;ve done isn&amp;rsquo;t necessarily wrong! You might consider checking it with the forall x proof checker.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FOL Parentheses</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/fol-parentheses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Nov 2020 13:59:37 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/fol-parentheses/</guid>
      <description>The following specifies where, for your work in this course, parentheses are and are not optional in First Order Logic:
 Textbook Section 26.4 allows us to omit the outermost brackets of any formula (so, “P⋁Q” is just as good as “(P⋁Q)”). And it allows square brackets (“[” and “]”) in place of parentheses wherever we feel it increases readability. Our textbook generally does not put parentheses around quantifiers, like ∀x and ∃x.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Variant Rule Names</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/variant-rule-names/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Nov 2020 11:39:33 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/variant-rule-names/</guid>
      <description>In the Basic deduction rules for TFL (summarized in textbook Appendix C, section 3.4), the names of the negation rules are a little confusing. I&amp;rsquo;m not the first instructor using this textbok to point this out. So, I offer you the following alternatives. In a natural deduction proof, in your justification column,
 you may optionally invoke the contradiction rule (¬E) by writing “contradiction” or “contra.” instead; because ¬I and IP are symmetrical rules1, but not named symmetrically, you may optionally invoke ¬I by calling it “IP”  In other words, I won&amp;rsquo;t mark those two alternatives wrong on homework or tests.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/test-2/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Nov 2020 16:32:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/test-2/</guid>
      <description>Test 2, administered at class time our Hofstra-assigned exam-time, 8–10 AM, on December 2, may include the following:
 Offer the definition of “logically valid.” Answer true-false questions using the terms/concepts from the vocabulary list, very similar to the true-false exercises you&amp;rsquo;ve done previously. Given a logically valid argument expressed in English, construct a symbolization key for the atomic sentences and/or names and predicates within them, in a way that&amp;rsquo;s adequate to bring out the logical validity of the argument.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Oct 2020 10:45:14 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some informative detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading, and it shows how grades are calculated for any particular assessment.
 4-point scale Test grades Overall course grades    4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Symbolization Exercise Answers</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/symbolization-exercise-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Oct 2020 16:20:47 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/symbolization-exercise-answers/</guid>
      <description>The answer sheet for the TFL symbolization exercise is here (pdf).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/test-1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Oct 2020 08:55:06 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/test-1/</guid>
      <description>Test 1, at class time on October 12, may include the following tasks:
 Define “logically valid.” Answer true-false questions using the terms/concepts from the vocabulary sheet, very similar to the true-false exercises you&amp;rsquo;ve done. Look at a few sentences, and construct a symbolization key for the atomic propositions in those sentences—one adequate to bring out their truth-functional structure. Using a symbolization key, symbolize English sentences in TFL. Using a symbolization key, translate symbolized TFL sentences into English.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>True/False Exercise Answers</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/true/false-exercise-answers/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 12:42:21 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/true/false-exercise-answers/</guid>
      <description>Answers to the true/false sentences exercise. Please ask if you&amp;rsquo;re not sure about any of them! I don&amp;rsquo;t think there are any errors.
 F F F F F T F T F F F T T T F F F F T T T F T F F T T F F T F F F F T T T T F F F T F T F T  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>vocabulary list</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/vocabulary-list/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Sep 2020 11:24:53 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/vocabulary-list/</guid>
      <description>These are technical words we have learned so far. Generally, you can find these words in the forall x book highlighted in pink small-caps. A student asked for a compiled list of them, for the purpose of making flash cards. So here it is:
 argument sentence true false truth value (logical) consequence (logical) validity (logical) invalidity (logical) soundness (logical) unsoundness inductive arguments deductive arguments case joint possibility joint impossibility contingency necessary truth necessary falsehood necessary equivalence truth-functional logic truth-functional connectives symbolization key atomic sentence expression of TFL sentence of TFL negation conjunction disjunction conditional biconditional conjunct disjunct antecedent consequent inclusive or exclusive or main logical operator scope (of a connective) use mention metavariable characteristic truth table natural deduction formal proof inference rules of TFL modus ponens affirming the consequent subproof additional assumption scope line discharging an assumption reductio ad absurdum indirect proof explosion derived rules disjunctive syllogism modus tollens First-order Logic (FOL) name singular term term predicate quantifier variable universal quantifier existential quantifier domain scope (of a quantifier)  (The parentheses indicate that we often use the word or phrase without the part in parentheses.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 6: Causation</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/causation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 11:09:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/causation/</guid>
      <description>We&amp;rsquo;ve discussed what correlations are, and how they are related to sampling from a population via basic probability ideas. But we noted that correlation isn&amp;rsquo;t causation, and that researchers are quite often interested in causation. Here we take up how it might be possible to investigate causal relationships, and some of the challenges and limitations inherent to doing that.
Reading  “Understanding and Misunderstanding Randomized Controlled Trials” by Angus Deaton and Nancy Cartwright.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 3</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Apr 2020 10:09:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/3/</guid>
      <description>As announced in class, upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 3” by Monday Apr 27.
At the end of page Hacking Chapter 18, answer questions 2–7.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 5: Frequentism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/frequentism/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Apr 2020 11:23:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/frequentism/</guid>
      <description>Next, we examine the second main, contemporary approach to scientific reasoning, based in the frequentist understanding of probability. At the heart of its reasoning is the “double negative” inference, based in the “probabilistic modus tollens.” The jargon name for this approach is “null hypothesis significance testing.” We will observe how and why it works, building up from some foundational concepts.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 16 “Stability” Hacking, Chapter 17 “Normal Approximations” Hacking, Chapter 18 “Significance and Power” (note on type I/II error)  Slides  Introducing null-hypothesis testing (Apr 13) Introduction to population sampling and correlation (updated Apr 16; slide 11 is new)  See also  “Statistical Tests, P Values, Confidence Intervals, and Power: A Guide to Misinterpretations” by Sander Greenland et al.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 17:23:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 2” by April 8 April 10.
Tasks   Write at least one sentence each about the following: a. What problem does Bayes&amp;rsquo;s rule address? b. In what way does it help with that problem? c. What is one kind of case where Bayesianism helps? d. What is a kind of case where Bayesianism seems less helpful?
  Do exercises 1–3, on Hacking page 77</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 2 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 10:41:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our second test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list; it&amp;rsquo;s now complete. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Bayesianism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 13:56:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</guid>
      <description>Bayesianism, as an approach to inductive reasoning, focuses on updating our beliefs in light of new evidence. It is built around a simple formula that expreses a relationship between probabilities.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 7 “Bayes&#39; Rule” (pages 69–77) Hacking, Chapter 13 “Personal Probabilities” (pages 151–160) Hacking, Chapter 21 “Learning from Experience as an Evasion of the Problem of Induction” (4 pages) — and if you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling sufficiently familiar with “the problem of induction,” look at the first pages of Chapter 20  See also  John Horgan, “Bayes&amp;rsquo;s Theorem: What&amp;rsquo;s the Big Deal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 1 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:30:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our first test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Probability</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 16:59:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</guid>
      <description>Here we set up some basic ideas about probability which will be key for understanding the approaches to scientific justification which have dominated the last several decades.
Reading  Hacking, Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic  Chapter 4 “Elementary Probability Ideas” Chapter 5 “Conditional Probability” Chapter 11 “What Do You Mean?”    Slides  Probability Probability-2  Note: These are PDFs which you should be able to view easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 14:47:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for Assignments by Feb 21.
Tasks   Produce your own original examples of:
 a deductively valid, sound argument a deductively valid argument which is not sound an inductively strong argument a version of that same argument which is even stronger an argument which sounds a little plausible and might actually persuade someone not being careful about their reasoning, but which is neither deductively valid nor inductively strong    Use your imagination and powers of observation a bit: What are some different ways inductive arguments can have more inductive strength than others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Early Methods</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:59:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</guid>
      <description>As modern science emerged, its practitioners tried to describe how they were reasoning, and how others should reason, to do science. They came to quite different answers! This unit looks quickly at a few landmarks from the period 1600–1900.
Reading  Francis Bacon, The New Organon (1620). Read Book 2, sections 10–16 (this starts on page 53 of the linked PDF), but skim through the examples to get a general sense of what&amp;rsquo;s going on with them, and focus on the beginning and end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:23:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</guid>
      <description>What is logic? What is deductive logic? Could deductive logic be the logic of science? Is non-deductive logic possible?
Reading (This is what you should read for this section. The due dates appear on the front page schedule.)
 Ian Hacking, An Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic (purchased book) Chapter 1 “Logic”, whole chapter, pages 1–7. Robin Smith, “Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Logic” in the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Read the brief/unnumbered preface then sections 1, 2, 3, and 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:25:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one written by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
