<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Content on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Content on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 15:26:52 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Apr 2020 17:23:09 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 2” by April 8 April 10.
Tasks   Write at least one sentence each about the following: a. What problem does Bayes&amp;rsquo;s rule address? b. In what way does it help with that problem? c. What is one kind of case where Bayesianism helps? d. What is a kind of case where Bayesianism seems less helpful?
  Do exercises 1–3, on Hacking page 77</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 2 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 10:41:20 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-2-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our second test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list, when it is complete. (The list is currently incomplete, and more questions will be added.) The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Bayesianism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 13:56:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</guid>
      <description>Bayesianism, as an approach to inductive reasoning, focuses on updating our beliefs in light of new evidence. It is built around a simple formula that expreses a relationship between probabilities.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 7 “Bayes&amp;rsquo; Rule” (pages 69–77) Hacking, Chapter 13 “Personal Probabilities” (pages 151–160) Hacking, Chapter 21 “Learning from Experience as an Evasion of the Problem of Induction” (4 pages) — and if you&amp;rsquo;re not feeling sufficiently familiar with “the problem of induction,” look at the first pages of Chapter 20  See also  John Horgan, “Bayes&amp;rsquo;s Theorem: What&amp;rsquo;s the Big Deal?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Test 1 Questions</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 08 Mar 2020 10:30:12 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/posts/test-1-questions/</guid>
      <description>The questions for our first test follow. They stick very closely to your readings and what we emphasized in class.
The test will consist of some of the questions on this list. The questions selected for the test will appear on the test exactly as they are written here. There will be at least eight of them on the test, of which you will need to choose six to answer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Probability</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 16:59:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</guid>
      <description>Here we set up some basic ideas about probability which will be key for understanding the approaches to scientific justification which have dominated the last several decades.
Reading  Hacking, Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic  Chapter 4 “Elementary Probability Ideas” Chapter 5 “Conditional Probability” Chapter 11 “What Do You Mean?”    Slides  Probability Probability-2  Note: These are PDFs which you should be able to view easily.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 14:47:58 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for Assignments by Feb 21.
Tasks   Produce your own original examples of:
 a deductively valid, sound argument a deductively valid argument which is not sound an inductively strong argument a version of that same argument which is even stronger an argument which sounds a little plausible and might actually persuade someone not being careful about their reasoning, but which is neither deductively valid nor inductively strong    Use your imagination and powers of observation a bit: What are some different ways inductive arguments can have more inductive strength than others?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Early Methods</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:59:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</guid>
      <description>As modern science emerged, its practitioners tried to describe how they were reasoning, and how others should reason, to do science. They came to quite different answers! This unit looks quickly at a few landmarks from the period 1600–1900.
Reading  Francis Bacon, The New Organon (1620). Read Book 2, sections 10–16 (this starts on page 53 of the linked PDF), but skim through the examples to get a general sense of what&amp;rsquo;s going on with them, and focus on the beginning and end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:23:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</guid>
      <description>What is logic? What is deductive logic? Could deductive logic be the logic of science? Is non-deductive logic possible?
Reading (This is what you should read for this section. The due dates appear on the schedule.)
 Ian Hacking, An Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic (purchased book) Chapter 1 “Logic”, whole chapter, pages 1–7. Robin Smith, “Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Logic” in the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Read the brief/unnumbered preface then sections 1, 2, 3, and 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2019 21:25:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/info/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one written by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>