<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Assignments on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Assignments on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:01:04 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 21:01:04 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 2” any time before the March 8 class. (I originally said Friday March 5, but I&amp;rsquo;m adding in some extra time, in case you want it.)
Tasks In chapter 2 (page 201, or 11) of Philosophy of Natural Science, Hempel quotes a statement of the scientific method from an economics textbook, and then develops several criticisms of it. The following asks you, similarly, to find similar example in the wild and to (briefly) critically analyze it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:19:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</guid>
      <description>Upload your page to “Assignment 1” on Blackboard, under the Assignments area (link in the left sidebar) by, at the latest, (anytime on) Feb 19.
Tasks   For this exercise, arguments take the form of two or more sentences — with at least three usually making things easier! — the last of which is the conclusion. The phrases in each sentence should fit together. See forallx, Chapter 2 for examples of arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/3/</guid>
      <description>title: &amp;ldquo;Assignment 3&amp;rdquo; draft: false date: 2020-04-24T10:09:13-04:00 tags:
 assignments   In the question set at the end of page Hacking Chapter 18, answer questions 2–7. Offer some explanation (maybe 1–2 sentences for each answer) in your own words. That is, think of each question that doesn&amp;rsquo;t already say “Why?” asking “Why?”
Please upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 3” by Monday Apr 21.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
