<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>assignments on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tags/assignments/</link>
    <description>Recent content in assignments on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 08:58:38 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tags/assignments/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 4</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/4/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Apr 2022 08:58:38 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/4/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 4” by April 25.
Tasks   Bayes without numbers: Suppose you have a hypothesis, on the first day of class, that the course will have 50% first-year students (FYS) in it. The evidence you have available to you is that when the first two students walk in, they are both first year-students. Without doing a calculation, write a paragraph discussing how you might use Bayes&amp;rsquo;s rule to think about how this evidence might change your confidence in your hypothesis.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 2</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:34:42 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/2/</guid>
      <description>Upload your assignment to the Blackboard link for “Assignment 2” by February 16.
Tasks   Find the brief sketch of scientific method you wrote out during our exercise in class.1 Write that out briefly.2 (about 3–4 sentences)
  Look at the steps in, or parts of, your representation of scientific method. Do any of the moves involve deductive reasoning? Do any of the moves involve inductive reasoning? (By “moves” I mean: If someone were to try to do science using your method, what are the steps they would probably take?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Jan 2022 22:17:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 3</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/3/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 04 Apr 2021 10:09:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/3/</guid>
      <description>In this assignment we use Whewell&amp;rsquo;s and Popper&amp;rsquo;s models of scientific reasoning and justification to understand scientific developments from the last couple months. Not all of the reasoning in the examples will fit the philosophical models, but your job is to look for how, or where, it does. For each of the following numbered items, write a short paragraph — at least several sentences.
 For one of the following Science News stories, describe (at least some important aspect of) the reasoning of the scientists who performed this research, in terms of William Whewell&amp;rsquo;s model of scientific method:   “An ancient impact on Earth led to a cascade of cratering” “Homo sapiens may have reached Europe 10,000 years earlier than previously thought”  For one of the following Science News stories, describe (at least some important aspect of) the reasoning of the scientists who performed this research, in terms of Karl Popper&amp;rsquo;s model of scientific method:   “Clovis hunters’ reputation as mammoth killers takes a hit” “Organic molecules in an ancient Mars meteorite formed via geology, not alien life” “Americans tend to assume imaginary faces are male” “Here’s what goldfish driving ‘cars’ tell us about navigation” “An arc of galaxies 3 billion light-years long may challenge cosmology”  For one of the two analyses above — either your Whewell example or your Popper example, that is: In what ways could the example fit the model of scientific method better?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assignment 1</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Feb 2021 09:19:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/assignments/1/</guid>
      <description>Upload your page to “Assignment 1” on Blackboard, under the Assignments area (link in the left sidebar) by, at the latest, (anytime on) February 9.
Tasks   For this exercise, arguments take the form of two or more sentences — with at least three usually making things easier! — the last of which is the conclusion. The phrases in each sentence should fit together. See (assigned reading) forallx, Chapter 2 for examples of arguments.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
