<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>notes on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tags/notes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in notes on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 16:52:50 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tags/notes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Method</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-method/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Mar 2021 16:52:50 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-method/</guid>
      <description>A first account of scientific method to think about </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Popper</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-popper/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Mar 2021 09:04:52 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-popper/</guid>
      <description>Popper&amp;rsquo;s criteria for falsifiability  A theory makes predictions, which are  capable of being false precise (not vague) about observable phenomena risky, unexpected or improbable based on current theories   The theory must actually be open to rejection if its predictions are false (if it&amp;rsquo;s &amp;ldquo;falsified&amp;rdquo;), not preserved by ad hoc excuses, exceptions, or reinterpretations not structurally resistant to falsification not treated as resistant to falsification  &amp;ldquo;ad hoc&amp;rdquo; = &amp;ldquo;for this&amp;rdquo; = introduced for a specific purpose</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Hempel</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-hempel/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Mar 2021 09:05:59 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-hempel/</guid>
      <description>Hempel Semmelweis Hypotheses:
 Atmospheric/cosmic hypothesis - but: effects are inconsistent with how this cause would work - significant data that is not explained by this cause Psychological hypothesis - test: removes and moves putative cause; outcome: effect doesn&amp;rsquo;t change Position of delivery hypothesis - test: removes putative cause; outcome: effect doesn&amp;rsquo;t change Cadaveric matter hypothesis - test: remove putative cause by hand-washing; effect: dramatic change further support: it explains the 1st/2nd ward mortality difference because the mechanism is absent in second ward, also explained mortality diff.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Whewell</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-whewell/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 24 Feb 2021 09:05:45 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-whewell/</guid>
      <description>Whewell The way we can think about collections of observations is to invoke hypotheses.
Speculatively, imaginatively inventing hypotheses is necessary for scientific discovery (“invention”).
 We only get true hypotheses by considering and rejecting many false ones. History of science shows creative invention of many hypotheses is the rule rather than the exception.  Johannes Kepler only yielded his laws of motion (orbits are elliptical) through wild speculation, and Kepler&amp;rsquo;s work was necessary for Newton&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Hume</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-hume/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Feb 2021 09:05:41 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-hume/</guid>
      <description>Hume Knowledge
 relations of ideas: the way ideas are connected [&amp;ldquo;3 x 5 = 30 / 2&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;Everything accurate is correct.&amp;quot;] - true as a function of the meanings of the ideas involved.  A statement for which, once we define the ideas, it&amp;rsquo;s necessarily true.   matters of fact: [&amp;ldquo;Moisture can cause mold.&amp;rdquo; &amp;ldquo;Turtles have shells.&amp;quot;]  A statement for which its contrary is still possible, in that it doesn&amp;rsquo;t imply a contradiction, and it can be conceived clearly by the mind.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Notes on Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Feb 2021 16:50:26 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/notes-on-logic/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Interpreting Grades</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jan 2020 19:55:28 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/interpreting-grades/</guid>
      <description>This note about grading and interpreting grades just adds some detail to what the course syllabus already says about grading.
4-point scale Grades in this course are assigned and calculated using Hofstra&amp;rsquo;s 4-point scale (described here in the Hofstra Bulletin). Following the Bulletin, the alphabetical grades, including plus (+) and minus (–), have the following 4-point scale values (and vice versa):
   letter 4pt Student’s academic performance …     A 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Participation Rubric</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/participation-rubric/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jan 2020 21:25:39 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/notes/participation-rubric/</guid>
      <description>This is the participation rubric to be used for grading participation in this course. Read it as saying “A student who demonstrates … earns a grade of X,” where X is the letter grade at the top of the column.1
   A B C D F     Active role in discussions, drawing on texts Regular, constructive participation drawing on texts Inconsistent constructive participation based on texts Vague comments reflecting limited engagement with texts Persistent lack of engagement with texts   Full preparation for approximately every class Substantial preparation, normally Inconsistent evidence of preparation Rare evidence of participation No positive evidence of participation   Success at advancing level and depth of discussion, persistently Regular contributions based on assigned material, which sometimes improve discussion and never diminish it Rare or no significant contribution to the level of discussion while not reducing it Activity sometimes diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment Activity regularly diminishing the discussion and the classroom environment   Active engagement with and listening to peers, persistently Sincere efforts to interact with peers, normally Limited engagement with peers Rare interaction with peers No interaction with peers      This rubric is significantly based on, and lightly adapted from, one shared by another philosophy professor, Jay Odenbaugh.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
