<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>topics on PHI 152</title>
    <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tags/topics/</link>
    <description>Recent content in topics on PHI 152</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 13:56:35 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/tags/topics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 4: Bayesianism</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 13:56:35 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/bayesianism/</guid>
      <description>Bayes&amp;rsquo;s rule is a simple piece of math. It expreses a relationship between probabilities. But it has been deployed as the heart of a solution to inductive reasoning which is called &amp;ldquo;Bayesianism.&amp;rdquo; We will working on understanding, and then begin to assess, this solution.
Reading  Hacking, Chapter 7 “Bayes&amp;rsquo; Rule” (pages 69–77) Hacking, Chapter 13 “Personal Probabilities” (pages 151–160) Hacking, Chapter 14 “Coherence” (pages 163–169)  See also  Elliott Sober, “Introduction to Bayesian Epistemology”  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 3: Probability</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Mar 2020 16:59:47 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/probability/</guid>
      <description>Here we set up some basic ideas about probability which will be key for understanding the approaches to scientific justification which have dominated the last several decades.
Reading  Hacking, Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic  Chapter 4 “Elementary Probability Ideas” Chapter 5 “Conditional Probability” Chapter 11 “What Do You Mean?”    See also  Hacking Chapter 3 “The Gambler&amp;rsquo;s Fallacy” sets up some basic ideas about chance devices, and Chapter 6 “The Basic Rules of Probability” summarizes the rules that appear in the above assigned chapters.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2: Early Methods</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 16:59:10 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/early-methods/</guid>
      <description>As modern science emerged, its practitioners tried to describe how they were reasoning, and how others should reason, to do science. They came to quite different answers! This unit looks quickly at a few landmarks from the period 1600–1900.
Reading  Francis Bacon, The New Organon (1620). Read Book 2, sections 10–16 (this starts on page 53 of the linked PDF), but skim through the examples to get a general sense of what&amp;rsquo;s going on with them, and focus on the beginning and end.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1: Logic</title>
      <link>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2020 19:23:28 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://chreliot.github.io/phi152/topics/logic/</guid>
      <description>What is logic? What is deductive logic? Could deductive logic be the logic of science? Is non-deductive logic possible?
Reading (This is what you should read for this section. The due dates appear on the schedule.)
 Ian Hacking, An Introduction to Probability and Inductive Logic (purchased book) Chapter 1 “Logic”, whole chapter, pages 1–7. Robin Smith, “Aristotle&amp;rsquo;s Logic” in the Stanford Encyclopedia of Philosophy. Read the brief/unnumbered preface then sections 1, 2, 3, and 6.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>